Ah , Satan , Mon Cher .
You are late , yes , you are . Still looking for your girlfriend , huh ?
Mademoiselle Dandelo has found another . You will never see her again .
But don 't you worry . There will be others .
Eh , madame ?
Yes ? Yes , who is this ?
This is François Delambre speaking .
Helene ? How are you , Helene , dear ? What can I do for you ?
François , I 've killed Andre .
- I need your help . - Now , look , Helene , it 's past midnight .
I 've had a hard day . I love you both dearly , but this sort of a joke ...
It 's true .
I 've killed Andre .
You killed ... But ...
Please help me .
Call the police and ... Come quickly .
I just can 't ...
Helene .
Helene ?
- Yes ? - Monsieur François ? Gaston .
I tried to call you . Something terrible has happened .
A man is dead . His head is under the press .
And I saw a woman running ... Running away .
Yes , Gaston .
It looked ... I think it was Madame Delambre .
You stay there , Gaston . I 'll get the police immediately .
Anthenium Club ? Is Inspector Charas still there ?
Yes , thank you . Yes , I 'll wait .
Check .
Sorry to interrupt , sir . There 's a call .
Thank you .
- Hello ? - Inspector ?
This is François Delambre . You may remember , we met a few times at the club .
It 's just ... I 'm sorry to call you so late ,
but , well , I 'm in terrible trouble .
- Trouble , monsieur ? - My sister-in-law just phoned .
She 'd killed her husband , my brother ... My brother , Andre .
What ? At our factory , Delambre Freres .
Our night watchman called too . There is a body .
Where are you now , Mr. Delambre ?
I 'll pick you up in a few minutes . Good-bye . You 'll have to excuse me .
- Inspector , Helene lives just ... - No , we ought to look here first .
- But I 've got to talk to her . - Please , I 've already sent a man .
She 'll be all right .
It 's Andre .
- How can we raise the press ? - I 'll do it for you .
Would you like us to get one of your men ?
I 'll be all right .
Whenever you 're ready , monsieur .
Dead about 30 minutes .
- Is the downstroke fast ? - No .
About the same .
- No danger of it coming down again ? - No .
It 's been set for 50 tons .
- Impact zero . - Zero ?
Yes . That means level with the bed .
- It 's never been set that way . Never . - Oh ?
That would squeeze the metal to nothing .
It 's been set for single strokes too .
She didn 't know how to operate the press .
- Are you sure this is your brother ? - Well , he ...
There was a long scar on his left leg . War wound .
- I 'll ... Would you mind ? - Doctor .
I can 't believe it .
Can you think of any reason why she would do such a thing ?
None . Absolutely none .
They were completely happy together .
They have a wonderful little boy , Philippe , whom they both adore .
Helene was always so gentle . It just doesn 't make sense .
Andre loved two things , his family and his work .
It 's impossible .
- What is it , monsieur ? - The stroke count .
- That 's the stroke count . - I don 't understand .
Whoever did this to Andre ... It reads two .
- They did it twice ! - Twice ?
Oui , monsieur . I heard the press come down two times .
- Good evening , monsieur . - Good evening .
- Is it true ? - Doctor .
Yes .
- Did Helene ... - Listen , I can 't believe it .
Inspector , this is our family physician , Dr. Ejoute .
- Inspector Charas . - Your man called me , so I came .
- How is she ? - Quite calm now .
Almost in a state of euphoria , of relief , as though she 's happy about it .
Is she insane , Doctor ?
Helene Delambre could 've never killed her husband .
It 's impossible . Unless she is or was insane .
- Did she tell you anything ? - Nothing , except she killed him .
And how ... No , there 's nothing in her that could make her do that .
Why , Inspector , I 've known her all her life .
I even delivered her .
She and Andre were devoted to each other .
- Where is Madame Delambre ? - In the living room .
François , I 'm sorry I called you .
As you see , I could 've called the police myself . I 'm all right now .
Helene , my dear , you know if there 's anything I can do ...
You 're the police ?
Inspector Charas , madame .
Helene , what 's going on ? Why do you say you killed Andre ? Why ?
It 's all right , François . Everything 's all right now .
Madame , would you tell us what happened ?
Of course , monsieur .
I killed my husband , Andre Delambre ,
about half an hour ago in the hydraulic press shed .
You understand the gravity of the crime .
You say you killed your husband . That means you murdered him .
I killed Andre , yes .
- Why ? - I cannot answer that question .
- How did you kill him ? - With the hydraulic press .
- How do you operate it ? - First you put on the main switch .
Then you set the stroke to whatever tonnage you want .
You set the stroke to maximum , that is , level with the table , or zero .
Then you press the release button . It 's the red one .
You mean you put your husband under the press ?
No , Inspector . He did that himself .
He put his head and his arm under the press ?
- Yes . - Why ?
I cannot answer that question . Coffee , Inspector ?
Yes , ple ... Gentlemen , would you wait for me outside , please ?
Yes , of course .
No , thank you .
Now , madame , you were happy with your husband ?
There were no mistresses . I had no lovers .
We were both very happy .
- That is the truth . - Then why did you kill him ?
I wish to help you all I can , Inspector , but I cannot answer that question .
You pressed the button and it was all over .
Yes .
- Why did you press it twice ? - Oh , it was only once .
The stroke count read two . A machine cannot lie .
Oh , yes . Yes , it was twice . I ... I was wrong .
- I did it twice . - Why ?
Perhaps you will wait , madame ?
Of course , Inspector .
What would you advise , medically , Doctor ?
Rest . Maybe in a day or two , her state of mind will improve .
Very well . You understand the lady is under surveillance .
I 'll arrange for one of our nurses to take charge of her .
Of course . Thank you very much , Inspector .
You can rely on me .
Well , what do you think ?
Would you show me your brother 's laboratory ?
Yes , of course . This way .
This is the work of a madman !
There was over $ 200,000 worth of special equipment here .
Andre was always so careful of everything .
Special equipment ? What was all this for ?
I don 't know . It could have been anything , any one of a dozen ideas .
He ... Well ... When he 'd develop something , he would show it to me .
He was working on an idea for the Air Ministry .
Perhaps they 'd know .
I imagine electronics is a profitable field these days .
Yes , very . We own the business jointly .
We both have more money than we know what to do with .
They had no outside interests . None , I 'm sure of it .
That 's why it doesn 't make sense .
You 're very attached to both of them , aren 't you ?
Yes . Inspector , what does all this mean ?
I have no idea .
She would tell me nothing except that she 'd killed him .
There appears to be no motive , no reason except insanity .
And even that leaves several important questions unanswered .
Perhaps he committed suicide .
Well , if he did , why does she say she killed him ?
And if it was suicide , why such a clumsy method ?
And why involve your wife ?
And she was there .
She could hang for this .
Poor Philippe .
What will I tell him ? How does one tell a child ?
If I may suggest , you could look after the boy for a while .
What 's gonna happen to her ?
We 'll keep her under observation for the moment .
There 's plenty of time .
Did your brother ever experiment with animals ?
Never .
- Or insects ? - Insects ? No .
That would be funny if ...
No , Helene and Andre believed in the sacredness of life .
They wouldn 't harm anything ,
not even a fly .
Lunch , madame .
Oh , I 'm eating much too much .
At this rate , I 'll gain pounds .
- Can I get up today ? - Ask Dr. Ejoute , madame .
Every time I ask him , he says " Tomorrow . "
You 're coming along nicely . The rest will do you good .
Is Inspector Charas coming today ?
He did not say , madame .
I like him . He 's been very gentle .
I hope François brings that nice little boy today .
What is his name ? Philippe ?
Yes , Philippe .
A nice boy .
They think I 'm mad , don 't they ?
They never tell me what they think about .
Go away .
Go away !
- Is it bothering you ? - No . No , it doesn 't bother me .
- I 'll soon rid you of the pest . - It 's all right , Nurse Andersone .
Please leave it alone ! But , nurse !
Stop it , nurse . Stop it !
Leave it alone ! Leave it alone !
- No ! No ! - What is the matter ?
- Let me look at that fly ! - You get back into bed !
- Please let me look at the fly ! - Back into bed .
Get out of my way ! Where is it ? Where ?
Oh . Oh , there .
Come on . Come on , madame .
- It 's just a common housefly . - Yes .
Perhaps it 's symbolic of something deep in her subconscious ,
as her psychiatrist believes .
Mr. Delambre , do you think she 's mad ?
It 's obvious , isn 't it ?
In spite of what the doctors think ,
I believe Mrs. Delambre 's mind is quite clear .
- Even when catching flies . - How can you say that ?
She must be mad . What about Philippe ?
She acts as if the boy were mine and not hers .
She may be trying to protect him .
- Perhaps she fears him or even hates him . - That 's impossible .
Helene couldn 't hate anyone . You must be out of your mind .
You 're in love with her , aren 't you ?
- Yes . - Then why didn 't you marry her ?
Because she loved my brother .
I don 't think she ever noticed me .
I 'm glad you 're being honest with me .
You see , at first I suspected you .
Me ? Why should I do such a thing ?
Motive one , for his wife . Motive two , to gain control of Delambre Electronics .
What do I care about motives ? Helene is in trouble and Andre 's dead .
It 's ... It 's like a nightmare .
I know now you had nothing to do with it , but I had to check for her sake .
I 'm sorry , Inspector . I 'm a fool .
You 've been so patient . Forgive me . It 's just ...
I understand , monsieur .
It is I who should apologize . I have to pry into all sorts of personal things .
It 's necessary , unfortunately .
Thank you for coming .
If there 's anything I can do to help , I will .
Did you discover what your brother was working on ?
No . The Air Ministry scientists have been through all of his papers . Everything .
They didn 't mean a thing to them .
We couldn 't decipher the ashes . Nothing there either .
Well , I 've delayed all I can . We 've been quite patient with the lady .
I 'm afraid I shall have to ask for a warrant tomorrow .
- The courts can decide . - Tomorrow ?
The charge can only be murder .
I 'm sorry for you and the boy ,
but I cannot conceive of any verdict except guilty ,
or guilty but insane .
- Thank you , Yvette . - Uncle ?
- Yes , Philippe ? - When 's Daddy coming home ?
- Soon . - Can I see Mommy again tomorrow ?
- Yes . - She 's very sick , isn 't she ?
Yes , Philippe , she 's very sick .
Do flies live a long time ?
I don 't know . Why ?
Because I saw that fly Mommy was looking for again .
I didn 't know your mother was looking for one .
Oh , yes , she was . It 's grown quite a lot ,
but I recognized it , all right .
- Mmm , this is good . - How did you recognize it ?
Its head is white instead of black ,
and it has a funny sort of leg .
It was on your desk this morning .
Oh ? I didn 't notice it .
When did you first see that fly ?
The day Daddy went away .
I had caught it , but Mommy made me let it go .
Then later she wanted me to find it again .
She changed her mind . You know how women are .
Excuse me , Philippe .
I won 't be a moment .
Inspector Charas .
- Good evening , Nurse . - Why , Mr. Delambre .
Inspector Charas told me about her relapse . How is she now ?
Resting quietly , poor lady . But monsieur ...
The inspector told me that I might speak to her for a few moments alone .
- He knows I 'm here . - But he didn 't say you were coming .
He has so much on his mind . I won 't be long .
Oh .
François , I didn 't hear you .
You look tired .
Of course . Just the office , you know .
You shouldn 't work so hard .
- How are you ? - I 'm fine . I feel all right .
I 'm glad you came . I wanted to ask you something .
Of course , Helene . Anything at all .
How long do flies live ?
Oh , I don 't know .
I think a month , two months .
The fly you were looking for was in my study today .
- Did ... Did you kill it ? - No .
You have it with you ? Give it to me .
- Please , give it to me ! - I haven 't got it here .
Oh .
- You know now . - What is this all about ?
You haven 't got it , or you wouldn 't ask .
Yes , I have it . It 's locked in my desk . Tell me what happened .
No , never . Andre wouldn 't want me to .
I know you 're not mad . I want the truth .
Either you tell me , or I 'm going to give it to Charas .
You swear you have it ?
Yes .
If I tell you , will you promise to destroy it ?
- I can 't do that until I know ... - Then I can 't tell you anything .
For your own sake you 've got to tell me .
You 're all right ,
or you can be all right perhaps .
As soon as they examine it they 'll know , and they 'll know you 're not insane .
No !
For Philippe 's sake , François , I beg you .
Don 't you see ? I was pretending to be mad for Philippe 's sake .
Better that I should be declared insane ,
than he should be the son of a woman hanged for murder .
I want to know .
Either you tell me now , or I give the fly to Charas .
If I tell you , will you tell them ?
I only want to help you .
I can only do that through them .
Yes , I would tell them .
Poor François .
Call Charas then . I can 't tell it twice .
So long as you 'll kill the fly .
You promise ?
Yes .
This is not a confession .
Although I killed my husband , I am not a murderess .
I simply carried out his last wish .
A few months ago ...
Who 's a ticklish boy ?
Why don 't you pick on somebody your own size ?
Andre ! What a pleasant surprise .
Hi , Daddy . Are you gonna play with us ?
Later , Philippe . I 've got to borrow your mother for a moment .
But I won 't be long , I promise .
I 'll tell you what .
Before you go to bed , I 'll play with you , all right ?
- Promise ? - Promise .
- All right then . I 'll play with Dandelo . - Good .
Be gentle with her , Philippe .
Come on . I 've got to show you something .
But , Andre , we don 't see you for days on end .
- Then suddenly you expect ... - Don 't argue with me . Come on .
But ...
I 'd no idea you 'd made so many changes .
- A completely new line of research . - Let me guess .
- The permanent battery . - Mmm-mmm .
Not the portable reactor ?
I 'll show you ,
but there must be absolutely no mention of this made to anyone .
- Of course . - It 's much too important .
Helene , you 're the first to see a miracle .
- Remember this ? - Oh , of course .
Our wedding present from my devoted and very rich Aunt Bess .
Mmm-hmm . The family heirloom .
Hurry , put them on .
Now watch the box .
You can take your goggles off now , darling .
It 's gone .
Come on .
- It 's the same one . - Mmm-hmm .
- Have you turned magician ? - In a way .
For a split second , an infinitesimal part of a second ,
this was disintegrated .
For one little moment it no longer existed ,
only atoms traveling through space at the speed of light .
Then here , a moment later , integrated again into the shape of an ashtray .
Oh , you 're joking .
Doesn 't sound possible , does it ? But it is true .
It is impossible . You 're playing some joke on me .
Take television . What happens ?
A string of electrons , sound and picture impulses ,
are transmitted through wires or the air .
The TV camera is the disintegrator .
Your set unscrambles , or integrates , the electrons back into pictures and sound .
- Yes , but this is different . - Why ?
Well , because it 's impossible !
Fifty years ago , if my father were told he could sit in Montreal ,
and watch a World Series in New York the exact time it was happening ,
he 'd say it was impossible .
- This is the same principle exactly . - But it 's not the same .
- This is solid . - Oh , no , it 's not .
To your touch , maybe it is . In reality , it 's billions of atoms ,
which we believe are only a series of electrical impulses .
Uh ...
You actually did this ? It 's no trick ?
No .
I can transport matter , anything , at the speed of light perfectly .
Oh , of course this is only a crude beginning .
But I 've been lucky enough to stumble on the most important discovery
since man sawed off the end of a tree trunk
and found the wheel .
The disintegrator-integrator will completely change life as we know it .
Think what it 'll mean . Food . Anything .
Even humans will go through one of these devices .
No need for cars or railways or airplanes , even spaceships . We 'll set up matter
transmitting-receiving stations throughout the world , and later , the universe .
There 'll never be a need of famine .
Surpluses can be sent instantaneously at almost no cost anywhere .
Humanity need never want or fear again .
I 'm a very fortunate man .
I 'm a very fortunate woman .
I hope you don 't transmit me . I wouldn 't want to come out like this .
What do you mean ?
Well , it doesn 't matter , does it , Andre ?
Andre .
It 's perfect . Everything checks .
It 's perfect .
Perfect .
Dandelo ! What 's the matter ? You hungry ?
There we are .
That 's it .
You won 't feel a thing , Dandelo .
And tomorrow you 'll be the most famous cat in all the world .
Dandelo !
Dandelo .
Hello ?
Oh , François , how nice to hear you .
Important ? You 're getting married .
No .
No , not yet . I think I like it this way .
It 's just that there 's no hurry . Is Andre there ?
Andre ?
I 've seen him about two hours in the last two weeks .
He eats and sleeps in his lab . He won 't talk or answer the telephone .
- I don 't want to hear one more word ! - I don 't want to !
- You 're going to eat your dinner now ! - I don 't want to !
Philippe 's acting like a juvenile delinquent . Dandelo 's disappeared .
I 've even got to go to Professor Augier 's this evening alone .
You know how he is , Helene .
It 's just until he solves his problem , whatever it is . Be patient .
How you men stick together .
Anything I can do ? All right , François . I 'll tell him if I see him .
I gotta run now , François . Good-bye .
Well ! Where have you been ?
Listen , darling , I 'm sorry about the last couple of weeks .
I had a little setback , but it 's all right now .
- Oh , I didn 't mind . - Hmm ?
Well , maybe just a little .
Call Augier and cancel out . We 're going to celebrate by ourselves .
Wonderful . I didn 't want to go anyway .
François just called about some special equipment . He 's sending it now .
Good . By the time you 've changed , I 'll be ready .
- Changed ? - I 've got tickets for the ballet .
- The ballet ! - We 'll eat at the Tour d 'Eiffel first .
- Oh , wonderful ! - Now hurry .
We 'll finish a delightful evening with reintegrated champagne .
Finish ?
- Well , not quite . - Oh ? What then ?
What do you suggest ?
You 're in an unscientific mood .
You don 't approve ?
I didn 't say that .
Will the champagne be as good as ever ?
Exactly the same , bubble for bubble .
Here .
- The label 's perfect ! - Of course !
Oh , it 's so cold !
And it 'll stay that way until I show you something else .
Oh ?
No , Andre , don 't ! It might not work . I won 't allow it !
- It 'll be all right . - Andre , please !
Put your goggles on , darling .
It 's astounding ! It works !
I test-ran it this morning . It 's all right .
You 've succeeded completely . It 's unbelievable .
We 'll have to wait and see . I 'll know for sure in a few weeks .
- I don 't understand . - To see if it suffers from ill effects .
- Oh . - If it 's alive in , say , a month ,
then we 'll pronounce the experiment successful .
May I look after him ?
It 's still a her , but you can .
For one whole month she 's mine .
Don 't kill her with overfeeding .
It 's a little frightening , isn 't it ?
Yes .
The first live experiment was disastrous ... Dandelo .
Dandelo ?
Andre , how could you ?
She disintegrated perfectly but never reappeared . I don 't know why , even now .
I redesigned the projecting device , and now it 's perfect .
Where 's she gone ?
Into space ,
in a stream of cat atoms .
It 'd be funny if life weren 't so sacred .
Andre , promise me one thing .
No more experiments with animals .
I promise . No more experiments with animals .
It 's frightening . It 's like playing God .
God gives us intelligence to uncover the wonders of nature .
Without the gift , nothing is possible .
Oh , Andre , I get so scared sometimes .
The suddenness of our age ,
electronics , rockets , Earth satellites , supersonic flight ,
and now this .
Oh , it 's not so much who invents them , it 's the fact they exist .
But you 're not frightened of TV or radio or X-rays or electricity ,
or that the Earth is round .
No , but everything 's going so fast .
I 'm ... I 'm just not ready to take it all in .
It 's ... It 's all so quick .
Just do like Philippe does .
Accept them as part of our normal life .
They 're facts , wonderful facts .
Which brings me back to the champagne .
I love you so much , Andre .
It 's wonderful being married to you .
And to you , my love .
You 're the healthiest guinea pig in the whole world .
Andre !
- You 'll catch cold . - Not today .
- What are you doing ? - Oh , just looking at the sky .
- Looking at God , perhaps . - You 're a strange man , Andre .
So precise and practical , and yet so ...
- I don 't quite know how to put it . - So aware of the infinite ?
The more I know , the more sure I am I know so little .
The eternal paradox .
You said you were frightened by progress .
I 'm filled with the wonder of it .
- Spring will soon be here . - I like spring the best .
All life growing , renewing itself .
- It 's fantastic to be alive . - How do you mean ?
Oh , I don 't know . It 's just ...
I 'm just so happy to be alive , that 's all .
So am I.
Would you marry me again if you had your time over ?
I think so .
Well , I 've got a lot to do .
- Oh , François is coming to lunch . - Oh ?
Bring him down to the lab . We 'll show him now .
Shall I call Professor Augier and the Air Ministry scientists too ?
Now , there 's no hurry .
I ... I don 't even know how or why parts of it work yet .
It 's too important . It 's too impossible .
Poor François . He 'll never believe it .
Don 't stay out too long , darling . You look tired .
The last thing I am is tired .
And we 're finishing with crepes suzette .
What 's all the celebration about ? I 'm only coming for lunch .
- Andre wants to show you something . - In the lab ?
- Mmm-hmm . - What is it ? Flat screen ?
It 's better . No more questions . Come on .
I 've only been invited into the laboratory three times .
Each time I came out with a potential fortune .
Oh , dear . We won 't see him for lunch .
I see what you mean . His writing gets worse and worse .
Mommy ! Mommy !
Where are you ?
Coming , Philippe .
Yes , darling ?
- I got something to show you . - I have something to show you .
I caught such a funny-looking fly . You want to see it ?
Let it go . You know your father disapproves of you catching insects .
But this isn 't like any other fly I 've ever seen .
It has a funny white head and sort of white leg .
Now , you let it go at once . Go along . Do as you 're told . Go on .
Look at all that dirt you brought in .
Best fly I ever caught .
- Was there anything else , madame ? - No , thank you . Good night .
Shall I leave something for the master ? Didn 't touch a bite of his dinner .
Oh ?
I fetched up his tray about an hour ago .
It was still outside the door . Had his favorite pastry on it too .
Never mind . He probably didn 't hear you knock . I 'll see if he wants anything .
Thank you . Good night , madame .
Good night , Emma .
Andre ? Andre , I 'm going to bed now . Is there anything you want ?
Andre !
" Helene , I 've had some trouble . "
Trouble ?
Andre , what 's the matter ? Answer me .
" I 'm counting on you not to lose your nerve , for only you can help me . "
" I 've had a serious accident . "
" But I 'm not in danger at the moment , "
" although it 's a matter of life or death . "
Andre !
" It 's no good calling to me or saying anything . "
" I can 't answer . I can 't speak . "
" You 've got to do exactly and very carefully what I tell you . "
" Knock three times to show you understand and agree , "
" then fetch me a bowl of milk laced with rum . "
Bowl of milk ? Andre !
- Anything I can do , madame ? - No . No , loan manage .
Go back to bed , Emma .
Good night , madame .
Ah !
" When you knock , I 'll open the door . "
" Walk over to my desk and put the milk on it . "
" Then go into the other lab and try to find a fly . "
A fly ?
" You will easily recognize it . Its head is white . "
Philippe -
Oh , Andre .
" Don 't hurt it . Just give it to me . "
" Before you come in , you must promise to obey me implicitly . "
" Do not look at me . Talking is useless . I cannot answer . "
" Knock three times to show I have your promise . "
" My life is in your hands . "
You can depend on me , darling .
It 's not in here .
If you can 't talk , knock .
Knock once for " yes " and twice for " no . " Do you understand ?
We 'll find the fly tomorrow . I promise .
Just as soon as it 's light , I 'll start looking .
Now , why don 't you go to bed ?
I 'll help you . No one will see you . I promise .
Philippe caught a fly this morning .
He said its head was white . I didn 't see it .
I made him let it go .
" Come back in morning . Will type explanation . "
" Need you fresh and strong tomorrow . Poor darling . Sorry . "
I 'm all right now , darling . Don 't worry .
I 'll find that fly .
Do you need anything tonight ?
Darling , please try and get some sleep .
Good night , darling .
Andre .
" Remember the ashtray experiment ?
" I 've had a similar accident . "
" I transmitted myself successfully yesterday morning . "
" But in the second experiment , a fly which I did not notice "
" was in the disintegrator with me . "
" When we integrated again , our atoms were mixed . "
" Now my only hope is to find the fly . "
" I 've got to go through the machine once more and pray our atoms untangle . "
" If you can 't find it , I 'll have to destroy myself . "
Can I come back in ?
Don 't worry , Andre . I 'll find that fly . It can 't be far away .
But you mustn 't talk about destroying yourself . You mustn 't .
I 'll call Professor Augier and the other scientists . They can help you . I ...
Don 't be angry , Andre . I only thought that ...
Promise me that you won 't do anything .
Let me see your face . I won 't be afraid .
All right .
All right , Andre . All right .
- Flies , madame ? - Yes . Close the windows .
- Catch flies ? - I told you , Emma .
A fly escaped from the lab . We 've got to find it .
- It 's got a white head . - Mommy !
I don 't know what 's gotten into this house .
Mommy !
- Look . I caught lots of them . - Where is it ?
- Are you sure you caught it ? - Oh , the white one .
No . I haven 't caught it yet .
I told you to find that fly .
I 'm sorry , Philippe , darling , but you 've got to find it .
The white one , only the white one .
- Gotcha ! - You fool !
I said catch them ! Don 't kill them !
I 'm sorry , Emma .
Please , just catch them .
Madame , there 's one in the hall .
Where ? Where is it ?
Oh , it 's no good , Emma . We 'll never find it .
Philippe ?
Make some supper , Emma , would you ?
I 'm sorry . It 's ... It 's just that ...
Come on , Philippe .
Go and get washed up for dinner . There 's a good boy .
All right , Mommy .
Oh , Philippe .
I see it .
Don 't move .
Go and get some sugar , quick .
Give me the sugar . And close those doors .
Now , stay back .
Got him !
- Good boy , Philippe . Careful now . - Let me see .
Oh , no .
It 's in back of the curtain !
Oh , don 't harm it .
Don 't hurt it .
Oh , God , don 't let it get out .
You try and keep it behind the curtain . I 'll get it from outside .
Oh , no . Oh , God ...
Please , God , don 't let it ...
Don 't cry , Mommy . Please don 't cry .
We 'll catch it tomorrow . Don 't worry .
Please don 't worry .
Andre .
We caught the fly today , but it escaped out into the garden .
I 'll look for it again tomorrow .
You eat . I 'll read this here .
" if you had caught the fly , you would not be reading this . "
" I know you will never catch it now . It 's hopeless . "
" There are things man should never experiment with . "
" Now I must destroy everything , all evidence , even myself . "
" No one must ever know what I discovered . It 's too dangerous . "
" I 've thought of a way . It 's not easy , but I need your help . "
Andre !
You can still reason , Andre . You 've got no right to destroy yourself .
You mustn 't think about it .
You 've still got your intelligence .
You 're still a man with a soul .
You 've no right to destroy yourself .
We 'll find that fly tomorrow . I know we will .
Think easy .
But you 've got to give me more time .
Why ? Why won 't you wait ?
Then see Professor Augier and the other scientists . They 'll help you .
They 'll do anything to help you .
I 've another idea . You remember the ashtray experiment ?
Go through again . It worked before .
Why ?
Please try it . You 've got to try it .
Please , Andre , for my sake .
Maybe it will work . I beg you .
Oh , darling , I love you and I want you so much .
Please , please let this come out right .
Hurry , darling . It will work .
It has worked , hasn 't it ?
You 'll be all right now . I know it 's worked .
No ! No ! No !
A strange story , Mrs. Delambre .
It 's almost impossible to believe , isn 't it ?
- What happened to his notes ? - He destroyed them .
- And the writing on the blackboard ? - I rubbed it out .
I see .
Well , I must be going . Thank you for telling me .
Inspector ,
it wasn 't wrong to destroy the thing ?
A fly-headed human ? No .
It wasn 't Andre . I couldn 't have hurt Andre .
But I 'm glad , I 'm glad the thing is dead .
I 'll see you out , Inspector .
- Inspector ... - I 'll be with you in a moment .
- Inspector ... - Do you believe the story ?
Well , it explains all the facts ,
the reason for the press , the fly , everything .
True . But I asked you if you believed it .
Oh , I 'm only a policeman , not a science fiction enthusiast .
But I do not believe what she said . It ... it can 't happen .
But you don 't ... Well , I ... I mean , you didn 't know Andre .
He was a genius in some ways .
Possibly . But matter cannot be transmitted . Oh , the story is impossible .
I 'll be back at 10 : 00 with a warrant for her arrest on the charge of murder .
Nurse Andersone is under strict instructions
not to leave her for any reason .
But , Inspector , it might be the truth .
It is the truth , to her .
I 'm satisfied now . She 's quite insane . She won 't hang .
- Well , I 'm not satisfied . - I wish I could help you , monsieur .
The lady 's in need of a doctor 's care , permanently .
There 's no telling whom she might attack next . Perhaps the boy .
But there must be something we can do to prove ...
There is .
Show me the fly .
- Good morning , Monsieur François . - Good morning , Emma .
- How 's the mistress , sir ? - Oh , as well as can be expected .
- Such a lovely lady . - Yes .
Emma , when you had that mad search for a fly , did you see it ?
- Oh , yes , I saw it . - What did it look like ?
Oh , just a fly . I 'd say it was a bluebottle .
You know , quite a large one .
- Did it ... Did it look any different ? - Not to me it didn 't .
She and Philippe were saying its head was white .
- But it was just a fly . - Thank you .
May I fix you some breakfast , sir ?
Nice cup of tea ? Some coffee ?
No , thank you .
Help ! Help me !
Help me !
Please help me !
We can manage quite easily . Thank you , Mr. Delambre .
Well , I ... I thought I ought to be here .
Do you wish to check the warrant ?
- As next of kin you have the right . - No , I 'm sure it must be all right .
- Madame ? Time to get up now . - Hmm ?
Oh , I slept so well .
- Wonderfully . Is it a nice day ? - Yes .
- I think I 'll have the silk one . - Take this one .
- You must be warm . - But I 'm not going out .
Come in .
- Good morning , Mrs. Delambre . - Inspector .
But I ... I don 't understand .
I have a warrant for your arrest for murder .
And I must caution you . Anything you say
can be taken down and used in evidence .
But , Inspector , I told you everything .
It is for the court to decide .
But you said it was not wrong to kill a thing .
- You have to come with us , madame . - François , didn 't you show them ?
You didn 't destroy it ?
Inspector , you saw it .
I 'm afraid I did not , Mrs. Delambre .
I lied to you , Helene . I never had it . I never had it .
You never had it ?
If you 'll just come with us , madame .
You never saw it ?
Leave her alone . She doesn 't have to go with you .
I demand that I first have time to talk to my attorney .
Dr. Ejoute will care for her .
I 've already consulted with him . The patient is ready to leave .
- I don 't believe it . - I have his diagnosis ,
- and his authority . - No , no , wait .
Don 't make things more difficult , monsieur .
- Here you go , ma 'am . You 'll be all right . - No !
François , don 't let them take me ! Don 't let them lock me up !
François , please ...
- Mommy ! Mommy ! - Philippe .
Oh , François , do something . Don 't let him see me like this .
Please !
Philippe . You can 't see her , Philippe , not at the moment .
I 'll take you for a walk . I know . I 'll take you to the movies .
But they don 't open till this afternoon .
Then I 'll take you this afternoon .
Is the ambulance for Mommy ?
Yes .
Is she going to be all right ?
Yes . All right .
- I ran all the way over here . - Oh ?
I wanted to see how she was .
- I wanted her to play with me . - She 'd like that , Philippe .
But she can 't , not now .
- When 's Daddy coming home then ? - Soon , Philippe .
- I saw that funny-looking fly again . - Oh ?
- Which show will we go to ? - Any ...
You saw the fly ? Where ?
It 's in a web . A spider 's going to get it .
By the bench in the garden .
- You 're sure ? - Oh , yes .
Stay here a minute .
- It 's in the garden . Come quickly . - Please , Monsieur Delambre ...
Philippe has seen it . It 's there . I beg of you . Please , please .
All right . Show me where .
Here , Uncle François .
Wait in the house .
There 's a good boy , Philippe .
Help me ! Please help me !
Help ! Help me !
Please help me ! Please !
Go away ! Go away !
No ! No ! No !
Charas .
I didn 't believe it , but you saw it .
- You saw it , didn 't you ? - Yes , I ... I saw it .
- I thought she was ... - As God is my witness , I saw the thing .
It 's unbelievable .
I shall never forget that scream as long as I live .
You 've committed murder , just as much as Helene did .
You killed a fly with a human head .
She killed a human with a fly head .
If she murdered , so did you .
I know . But who 's going to believe us ? They 'll think we 're both mad .
But he could have started the press and got under it in time .
It could have been suicide .
Andre 's mind was deranged . Helene just tried to stop him .
But the stroke count ?
I was the one who forgot to reset it after it was used the last time .
Yes . Yes . It could have been suicide .
Oh , a great shot , Philippe .
- Oh , François . Thank you . - Hello . You look wonderful .
- Hi , Uncle François . - Hi , Philippe .
You taking me to the zoo like you promised ?
- Yes , if your mother ... - Oh , you two run along .
We 'll all have dinner together later .
Oh , good .
- Uncle . - Yes ?
Mommy told me about Daddy .
Something she said to ask you .
Why did he die ?
Well , Philippe ,
he died because of his work .
He was like an ... Like an explorer in a wild country ,
where no one had even been before .
He was searching for the truth .
He almost found a great truth .
But for one instant , he was careless .
- That 's what killed him ? - Search for the truth
is the most important work in the whole world and the most dangerous .
I 'd like that . I 'd like to be an explorer like him .
- Will you help me , Uncle François ? - Yes , Philippe .
- You better run and get a coat . - Yes . Right away .
You 're a dear one , François . So kind and thoughtful .
Thank you .
Here I am .
Well , come along , you two . I 'll see you off .